在創世紀,神創造的世界是多少天的?
是多少天的?六天?
七天
七天是怎樣的?
七天是神創造甚麼世界?
Let there be light
And then there was ground and water, right?
And then there was stars covering the light
And then there was trees, water, fish, land animals
And then there was human
那麼神創造我們是怎樣的?
神創造你們是怎樣的?
是made in what image?
神創造的形象
是嗎?
We are made in the image of monkeys?
We are not
We are made in the image of God
Very good
Tell your neighbor
We are made in the image of God
但是呢
阿彌陀佛就怎樣?
之後又怎樣?
他吃了甚麼?
他吃了
The fruit of the knowledge of good and evil
之後又怎樣?
紅神就有甚麼?
有separation
然後上個禮拜Pastor Eddie就和我們說
The first murder
Who murdered who?
天murdered evil
天就說
Yo, let's go to the forest
然後怎樣?
他就kill了evil
That was the first murder
今天我們會看四樣東西
我們看四樣東西
We are going to look at hope, blessing, mercy and rest
Hope, blessing, mercy and rest
我們一起看創世記第五章
Let's read together
我們讀中文
1,2,3
When God created mankind, he made them in the likeness of God. He created them in male and female, but he made them in mankind when they were created.
When Adam lived 130 years, he had a son in his own likeness, in his own image, and he named him Seth.
After Seth was born, Adam lived 800 years and had other sons and daughters. All together, Adam lived a total of 930 years, and then he died.
我們看下一頁
亞當夏娃有三個兒子,Kane是大兒子,Abel是小兒子,他第幾歲就有Seth
130 years old
How old is your grandfather?
你最大的公公是多少歲?
Amazing
這個世界紀錄
可能是現代世界紀錄
但是130歲就有Seth
Seth有一個新的血統
我們看下一頁
這是Adam和Eve
在Eden的花園
他們930歲
他們130歲就有Seth
So you see that they are living together
Seth有一個兒子
Ethnos
Grandson
然後這個
Cainan
Cainan是Adam的什麼?
Great great great grandfather
誰認識他?
有沒有人認識他?
但是我們看到
這些人在創造世界的時候
為什麼可以存在這麼久?
900多歲
Imagine you have 900 years old
Uncle Vincent不用說多少歲
Imagine you are 900 years old
What would you do with your life?
900 years old
你會有多少個狗?
How many dogs have you had now?
He has 8 dogs
So imagine
He is 900 years old
Maybe times 9
我們問問自己
為什麼以前的人可以
800多歲?
有沒有人知道為什麼?
How come they could live so long?
How come?
什麼?
弟弟
We need more junk food
More junk food?
今天誰吃過junk food?
Uncle Vincent我知道你吃了很多junk food
You eat a lot of candy
Sweaty
Not 100, 900 years old
為什麼?
What do you think?
Has God left them?
Yes, maybe
之前的世界
可能不同
沒有污染
之前的世界
They say it might be
Protected by the
Waters above the firmament
以前的世界
可能不同
Before
Sin entered
The world might have been different
沒有污染
所以有很多不同的理論
知道為什麼
神創造
其實神創造人
They were supposed to live with God
多久?
神創造人
Lived for how long?
They were supposed to live with God forever
Right?
但是亞當夏威就怎樣?
犯了罪
Death was entered into the world
死亡就entered the world
所以我們看到
時間線變得更小
因為死亡
污染了世界
下一頁
我們看到
亞當夏威
930歲
他不是
Lived 900 years
然後才有Seth
然後才有Ethnos
然後才有Canaan
It's like a family
你們哪一天
有Family Dinner?
Friday
Friday night
我Friday有TU
所以沒有Family Dinner
誰是星期六有Family Dinner?
Andrew
誰是星期日晚有Family Dinner?
Dawn
有些人沒有Family Dinner?
Family Lunch
Can you imagine
亞當夏威和Seth和Canaan
Do you think they had Family Dinner?
可能不會是星期日
Let's have family dinner
就是吃飯
亞當和夏威很strict
你星期日晚一定要回來
吃飯
媽媽Eve會煮飯
煮什麼?
蝦餃燒賣
有紅豆冰
小糖小冰
還有什麼?
可能
Canaan一殺了Abel
他就有Family Dinner
就沒有了Family Dinner
可能又有衝突
誰的家庭
因為有衝突就沒有了Family Dinner
你一集可以分享
So imagine
亞當和Eve
He knew
They knew all the grandchildren
They lived together
我們不知道他們是一起住
還是分開住
我們不知道他們
一個住在銅鑼灣
一個住在九龍
要swim across the harbor
才拍到媽媽
不知道
They knew each other
They knew they had a relationship
Let's go to the next slide
The Curse of Sin
我們看到
Adam lived
900 something years
Seth lived
然後又死了
我們看到亞當和Eve
一犯了罪
就有罪的consequence
罪的consequence是什麼?
Dust you are
Dust you will return
神怎樣創造我們
他用什麼?
他用Dust
Breathe into dust
因為我們犯了罪
亞當和Eve就說
You will return to the dust
Adam was created in the image of what?
Adam was created in the image of God
Not dust
Seth
Was created in the image of Adam
因為Adam犯了罪
Seth就有
罪的後果
He has original sin
所以因為我們
個個都有一個
很selfish
一個natural desire
Do you have to teach a kid to lie?
No
You have to teach them to be good
因為我們
因為亞當夏娃
我們有罪的consequence
有罪的consequence
那為什麼神保留
這個新的Bloodline
為什麼不用Cain的Bloodline
因為Abel沒有了
Abel的Bloodline沒有了
為什麼他有一個新的Bloodline
Let's look at the next slide
他就說
I will put enmity between you and the woman
and between your offspring and her offspring
You shall bruise your head
and you shall bruise his heel
這個是神和誰說的
神是和那個
the snake
說的
一個consequence是什麼
The consequence is one day
her offspring
will bruise your head
這個offspring之後是誰來的
Who does it foreshadow
Jesus
comes from the Bloodline of Adam and Eve
and then Abraham
and then King David
and then Jesus
耶穌是亞當夏娃的Bloodline
through the
Bloodline of Seth
and that fulfills
the prophecy
that God is a God of Hope
God is a God of Hope
他不只是
Let Cain and Abel
situation happen
and that's it
Create a new Bloodline
through Seth
又一個new promise
He is the God of Hope
我們現在會分組
有幾個問題
第一個問題是
How many generations do you know in your family line?
Where are they from?
What did they do?
可能你爺爺公公
在上海
或者廣州
你可以說說他們做什麼
以前可能是打工
或者做工廠
第二個問題是
神怎樣介紹
Gospel在你家裏
我認識其他人
我認識
我爺爺的父母
他們之前做什麼
他們之前在大陸
流亡
我曾經做過一個project
知道我是誰三年前
神怎樣介紹
我爺爺的父母
之前已經是神
有一樣東西
很有趣
我媽媽在教會認識
他們的關係
我現在也是在教會
其實很有趣
如果你認識你
你認識你祖父
你認識你的故事
很有趣
因為這是一個奇蹟
你爸爸和你媽媽
你的祖父和祖母
你祖父和祖母
這是一個奇蹟
我們繼續看下一個句子
Seth住了105年
Seth住了106年